<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>855</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Combination ivermectin plus diethylcarbamazine, a new effective tool for control of lymphatic filariasis</title><description>In 1993, a three arm double-blind controlled trial was implemented in French Polynesia, to compare the tolerance and efficacy of single doses of the combination ivermectin (IVR) 400 mu g.kg(-1) plus diethylcarbamazine (DEC) 6 mg.kg(-1) vs. IVR 400 mu g.kg(-1) or DEC 6 mg.kg(-1) alone, for treatment of Wuchereria bancrofti carriers. Of the 57 treated male patients in whom microfilaremia (mf) densities ranged from 22 to 4,709 mf/ml, three groups of 19 were randomly selected, and allocated to one of the three treatments. Twelve months after treatment 37 %, 16 % and 16 % of patients were mf negative in groups DEC, IVR and IVR plus DEC respectively. Mf percent return to pretreatment level was significantly lower in the group IVR + DEG (1.9 %) than for DEC 6 (14.7 %) or IVR 400 (11.6 %). Antigenemia percent return to pretreatment level was lower in the groups IVR + DEC or DEC 6 than for IVR 400. The combination IVR + DEC proved to be the most effective on macrofilariae and microfilariae (antigenemia and mf negative patients). The combination will be a very powerful tool for control of lymphatic filariasis. An annual filariasis day could be the most cost-effective strategy for administration of the drugs.</description><year>1995</year><authors>Moulia-Pelat, J.P., Glaziou Ph., Weil, G.J., Nguyen, L.N., Gaxotte Ph., Nicolas, L.</authors><journal>Tropical Medicine and Parasitology</journal><volume-issue>46(1)</volume-issue><pages>9-12</pages><work_location>French Polynesia</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>French Polynesia/Moulia-Pelat et al 1995a Trop Med Parasitol 04022016103825-0001.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>1990</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>