<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>527</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Mapping, monitoring, and surveillance of neglected tropical diseases: towards a policy framework</title><description>As national programmes respond to the new opportunities presented for scaling up preventive chemotherapy programmes for the coadministration of drugs to target lymphatic filariasis, onchocerciasis, schistosomiasis, soil-transmitted helminthiasis, and trachoma, possible synergies between existing disease-specific policies and protocols need to be examined. In this report we compare present policies for mapping, monitoring, and surveillance for these diseases, drawing attention to both the challenges and opportunities for integration. Although full integration of all elements of mapping, monitoring, and surveillance strategies might not be feasible for the diseases targeted through the preventive chemotherapy approach, there are opportunities for integration, and we present examples of integrated strategies. Finally, if advantage is to be taken of scaled up interventions to address neglected tropical diseases, efforts to develop rapid, inexpensive, and easy-to-use methods, whether disease-specific or integrated, should be increased. We present a framework for development of an integrated monitoring and evaluation system that combines both integrated and disease-specific strategies.</description><year>2010</year><authors>Baker, M.C., Mathieu, E., Fleming, F.M., Deming, M., King, J.D., Garba, A., Koroma, J.B., Bockarie, M., Kabore, A., Sankara, D.P., Molyneux, D.H.</authors><journal>The Lancet</journal><volume-issue>375(9710)</volume-issue><pages>231-238</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/Baker et al 2010 LANCET Mapping Monitoring and Surveillance of NTDs.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>