<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1213</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Guidelines and Instructional Materials</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection;WHO Geneva</hardcopy_location><title>Guidelines for certifying lymphatic filariasis elimination</title><description>Overview: Widespread interest in and support for a global campaign to eliminate lymphatic filariasis has developed and grown in the 1990s. In 1997 the World Health Assembly endorsed efforts to eliminate transmission of filariasis on a country by country basis (WHA resolution 50.29). Filariasis is a disease which is endemic in communities worldwide affecting an estimated 120 million persons. Table 1 lists those countries where human filariasis has been: (i) endemic during the 1980s and 1990s, (ii) endemic or possibly endemic before 1980 but not recognized since then, (iii) sporadically reported without evidence of endemic disease. In 1998, there is still lack of knowledge about when transmission of filariasis was interrupted in many countries. The need for certification of attainment is inherent in the goal of an elimination programme; such a need does not exist for control programmes. There must be an objective basis, according to agreed criteria, for determining whether transmission of filariasis has indeed been eliminated; the criteria must take into account the risk of importation from filariasis endemic countries. It is expected that efforts towards elimination of filariasis transmission for individual countries will be conducted until the global certification of elimination of filariasis is achieved. In order to complete the process of certifying elimination, an independent International Commission for the Certification of Lymphatic Filariasis Elimination (ICCLFE) will be established by World Health Organization (WHO). This commission will recommend to the Organization those countries that fulfil the requirements for certification, as well as advise the Organization on criteria, procedures and progress made towards elimination of filariasis transmission. The commission will also designate a panel of specialists, whose members can be assigned to International Certification Teams (ICTs). WHO, including the Regional offices, will facilitate national preparations for certification by carrying out regular visits by WHO staff, members of the designated ICT, or consultants to the country or sub-region concerned. A register will be established of countries requesting certification and also of those countries where official certification of elimination is pending. Finally WHO will also establish an official register of countries where filariasis has been eliminated, ba5ed on evaluations by the ICCLFE. The aim of the present document is to describe the criteria for verifying the absence of filariasis transmission. In addition WHO has developed a document addressing issues of disease ascertainment, monitoring, and pre-elimination surveillance - i.e., addressing the various issues before elimination certification (see document WHO/FIL/99.195).</description><year>1998</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>20</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Freely available from publisher website</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_1213.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>1990</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>