<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1371</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Newsletters</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Integrated vector management to control malaria and lymphatic filariasis</title><description>The World Health Organization (WHO) promotes integrated vector management (IVM) to improve the cost effectiveness of vector-control operations, and to strengthen the capacity of programmes, partnerships and intersectoral collaboration in their efforts to control vector-borne diseases.1 IVM is a system of rational decision-making developed to optimize the use of resources for vector control (Box 1). The IVM approach aims to contribute to achieving the global targets set for vector-borne disease control by making vector control more efficacious, cost-effective, ecologically sound and sustainable. This document addresses the use of IVM for two of the most important vector-borne diseases: malaria and lymphatic filariasis. The IVM approach is useful and appropriate for jointly managing control activities against malaria and lymphatic filariasis in terms of planning, implementation and monitoring, particularly in areas where both infections are transmitted by the same species of mosquito vectors. IVM may concurrently reduce the incidence of both diseases so that control efforts have synergistic effects. In this way, IVM enables resources to be used more efficiently to control multiple vector-borne diseases and thus they have a greater impact on public health than would be the case with control programmes aimed at a single disease.</description><year>2011</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>4</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Freely available from publisher website</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_1371.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>