<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>2179</PacELF_ID><type>Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Filarial infection in vector mosquitos after mass drug administration in Western Samoa</title><description>In order to control filariasis in Western Samoa, the first round of mass administration of diethylcarbamazine was carried out between 1965 and 1966, without undertaking any vector control measures. Four yr of post control entomologic evaluation has revealed that the infection rate has dropped from 8.35% to 0.61% (1/14 of pre control rate) in Aedes (Stegomyia) polynesiensis and 4.47% to 0.26% (1/17 of pre control rate) in Aedes (Finlaya) samoanus; and the infective rate has dropped from 2.95% to 0.070% (1.42 of pre control rate) in Ae. polynesiensis and 0.26% to 0 in Ae. samoanus. More reduction was observed in the infective rate than the infection rate, presumably because of a remarkable decrease in the number of filarial larvae in infected mosquitos. It is suggested that, for the entomologic evaluation of filariasis control, the infective rate should be preferred to the infection rate. Of the three infective Ae. polynesiensis detected after the campaign, one was found three mth after its completion and the other two at least 1 yr later. No difference has been observed in the infection rate in mosquitos between different geographic locations. The drug distribution coverage was significantly less in the districts with infected mosquitos than in those where no infected mosquitos were found.</description><year>1975</year><authors>Suzuki, T., Sone, F.</authors><journal>Tropical Medicine</journal><volume-issue>16(3)</volume-issue><pages>147-156</pages><work_location>Samoa</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><decade>1970</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>