<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>2177</PacELF_ID><type>Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Distribution of vectors, transmission indices and microfilaria rates of subperiodic Wuchereria bancrofti in relation to village ecotypes in Samoa</title><description>Aedes polynesiensis and Ae. samoanus biting densities and Wuchereria bancrofti infection and infective rates were studied in 47 villages throughout the islands of Samoa Upolu, Manono and Savaii during 1978-79, and microfilaria (mf) rates were surveyed in 28 of the villages. The mf rate was correlated with both infection and infective rates of Ae. polynesiensis in Upolu, but not of Ae. samoanus. In Upolu, Ae. polynesiensis was apparently the major vector. It was relatively more abundant in more cultivated and populated areas, along the northern coast of Upolu, except Apia town area. In Savaii, Ae. samoanus predominated over Ae. polynesiensis except in "plantation" villages. Relatively high biting densities and rates of infection and infectivity indicated that Ae. samoanus was not less important than Ae. polynesiensis as a vector in Savaii. Ae. samoanus preferred natural vegetation, in contrast to Ae. polynesiensis which was found near human habitations in cultivated land. There was no difference between the biting densities of Ae. polynesiensis in "coastal" and "inland" villages, indicating that crab holes (numerous only in some coastal villages) may not influence the density of Ae. polynesiensis. Higher mf rates were associated with villages where Ae. polynesiensis, rather than Ae. samoanus, was dominant, indicating that Ae. polynesiensis was generally a more efficient vector. In the former villages, the difference in mf rates between males and females was smaller than in the latter, probably reflecting a difference in biting habits of the vectors. Ae. polynesiensis infections were recorded in plantations over 2 km from any village, suggesting that both habitats were foci of transmission.</description><year>1987</year><authors>Samarawickrema, W.A., Kimura, E., Spears, G.F.S., Penaia, L., Sone, F., Paulson, G.S., Cummings, R.F.</authors><journal>Transactions of the Royal Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene</journal><volume-issue>81(1)</volume-issue><pages>129-135</pages><work_location>Samoa</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><decade>1980</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>