<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1990</PacELF_ID><type>Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Detection of Brugia malayi in laboratory and wild-caught Mansonioides mosquitoes (Diptera: Culicidae) using Hha I PCR assay</title><description>An Hha 1 based polymerase chain reaction (PCR) assay developed for the detection of Brugia malayi, the causative agent of Brugian lymphatic filariasis, was evaluated for its sensitivity in the laboratory and for its usefulness in measuring changes in transmission of the disease in the field. Laboratory studies showed that the new assay was highly sensitive in comparison with the standard dissection and microscopy technique. The assay can detect as little as 4 pg of parasite DNA or a single microfilaria in pools of up to 100 mosquitoes. The optimum pool size for convenience was found to be 50 mosquitoes per pool. The efficacy of PCR assay was evaluated in filariasis control programmes in operation in endemic areas of Kerala State, South India. The infection rates obtained by the Hha I PCR assay and the conventional dissection and microscopy technique were 1.2% and 1.7% respectively in operational areas and 8.3% and 4.4% respectively, in check areas, which were not significantly different (P &lt; 0.05). Thus, the Hha I PCR assay was found to be as sensitive as the conventional technique and hence it can be used as a new epidemiological tool for assessing parasite infection in field-collected mosquitoes.</description><year>2001</year><authors>Hotia, S.L., Vasukia, V., Lizottea, M.W., Patraa, K.P., Ravia, G., Vanamaila, P., Manonmania, A., Sabesana, K., Krishnamoorthya, S., Williamsa, S.A.</authors><journal>Bulletin of Entomological Research</journal><volume-issue>91(2)</volume-issue><pages>87-92</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>