<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1001</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Mass drug administration trial to eliminate lymphatic filariasis in Papua New Guinea: changes in microfilaremia, filarial antigen, and Bm14 antibody after cessation</title><description>Laboratory tools to monitor infection burden are important to evaluate progress and determine endpoints in programs to eliminate lymphatic filariasis. We evaluated changes in Wuchereria bancrofti microfilaria, filarial antigen and Bm14 antibody in individuals who participated in a five-year mass drug administration trial in Papua New Guinea. Comparing values before treatment and one year after four annual treatments, the proportion of microfilaria positive individuals declined to the greatest degree, with less marked change in antibody and antigen rates. Considering children as sentinel groups who reflect recent transmission intensity, children surveyed before the trial were more frequently microfilaria and antibody positive than those examined one year after the trial stopped. In contrast, antigen positive rates were similar in the two groups. All infection indicators continued to decline five years after cessation of mass drug administration; Bm14 antibody persisted in the greatest proportion of individuals. These data suggest that Bm14 antibody may be a sensitive test to monitor continuing transmission during and after mass drug administration aimed at eliminating transmission of lymphatic filariasis.</description><year>2008</year><authors>Tisch, D.J., Bockarie, M.J., Dimber, Z., Kiniboro, B., Tarongka, N., Hazlett, F.E., Kastens, W., Alpers, M.P., Kazura, J.W.</authors><journal>American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene</journal><volume-issue>78(2)</volume-issue><pages>289-293</pages><work_location>Papua New Guinea</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Papua New Guinea/Tisch et al 2008 AJTMH MDA trial to eliminate LF PNG.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>