<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>477</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Towards eliminating lymphatic filariasis in Papua New Guinea: impact of annual single-dose mass treatment on transmission of Wuchereria bancrofti in East Sepik Province</title><description>The impact of annual single-dose community-wide treatment on the transmission of Wuchereria bancrofti was investigated in 5 villages in the East Sepik Province where pretreatment prevalence of microfilaraemia ranged from 34% to 73%. Anopheles punctulatus and An. koliensis were the only carriers of the parasite. 3 villages received diethylcarbamazine citrate (DEC) in combination with ivermectin (IVR) and 2 received DEC alone. The rate and intensity of microfilaraemia were both reduced in all 5 villages. Reduction in prevalence was between 43% and 67% in the DEC+IVR study villages and between 24% and 27% in the DEC alone villages. Density was reduced by between 81% and 95% in the DEC+IVR villages and between 69% and 74% in the DEC alone villages. Breaks in perennial transmission (failure to detect infective mosquitoes in four or more consecutive monthly collections) occurred in all 3 communities treated with DEC+IVR. Transmission was almost completely interrupted in 2 villages, where infective mosquitoes were not detected during 11 of the 12 months following treatment. We concluded that repeated annual single-dose community-wide treatment with DEC+IVR could lead to complete interruption of transmission and ultimately elimination of lymphatic filariasis.</description><year>2000</year><authors>Bockarie, M.J., Ibam, E., Alexander, N.D.E., Hyun, P., Dimber, Z., Bockarie, F., Alpers, M.P., Kazura, J.W.</authors><journal>Papua and New Guinea Medical Journal</journal><volume-issue>43(3-4)</volume-issue><pages>172-182</pages><work_location>Papua New Guinea</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Papua New Guinea/Bockarie et al 2000b PNG Med J Towards eliminating LF PNG.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>