<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>75</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Reduction of the scrotum by scrotomectomy and plasty in the surgical treatment of large hydroceles in lymphatic filariasis endemic countries</title><description>Objective: to classify our techniques of reduction of the scrotum by resection or "scrotomectomy", with plasty for large hydroceles. Patients/Method: We developed three main types of scotomectomy-plasty: unilateral, bilateral and resection of the inferior pole, utilized in a series of 50 scrotomectomy-plasty in a homogeneous series of 148 hydrocelectomy in 117 patients. Results: 92% of patients treated by scrotomectomy-plasty had a hydrocele at an advanced stage (54% stage III and 38% stage IV). In 24% of preoperative indications for scrotomectomy-plasty we observed during surgery a sufficient retraction of the scrotum to prevent it. Thus, out of 1 17 patients 43% had a scrotomectomy-plasty. We recorded 6 complications, all in hydroceles stages III or IV with scrotomectomy-plasty. Five of these patients had a hematocele or chylocele. Two did not benefit from our compressive dressing. These complications only delayed by a few days the complete cure. In all cases the esthetic result was very satisfactory. Conclusion: The esthetic and functional result of hydrocelectomy is significantly completed through resectionplasty of the scrotum without increasing the postoperative morbidity in the immediate and close follow up. The three main types of scrotomectomy-plasty that we developed and utilized allowed us to properly manage all stages from I to IV of our clinical classification.The technique should be extended to other homogeneous series for a more precise codification of the procedures as outlined and a review of patients on distant follow up.</description><year>2013</year><authors>Capuano, G.P., Capuano, C.</authors><journal>Fiji Journal of Public Health</journal><volume-issue>2(2)</volume-issue><work_location>Fiji</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Fiji/PacELF_75 Capuano and Capuano 2013 FIJI J PUB HLTH Reduction of the scrotum by scrotomectomy and plasty.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>