<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>784</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Age-grading and growth of Wuchereria bancrofti (Filariidea: Onchocercidae) larvae by growth measurements and its use for estimating blood-meal intervals of its Polynesian vector Aedes polynesiensis (Diptera: Culicidae)</title><description>Growth in length and width of Wuchereria bancrofti (Filariidea: Onchocercidae) larvae developing in its Polynesian vector Aedes polynesiensis (Diptera: Culicidae) was analysed using a mathematical approach to objectively extract patterns. L1 had a U-shaped growth in length, while widths followed an S-shaped function. L2 had an S-shaped growth in length and width. Growth in length of L3 was also S-shaped, while widths had an asymptotic size following a period of rapid shrinkage. The greatest difference between length and width was in stage 3 where the length was over 75 times greater than the width. The ratio of length to width was approximately 50 for microfilariae and only 10 for the L1 ('sausage') stage. Characteristic mean length (and width) were approximately 280(7) microm for microfilariae, approximately 181 microm for L1 at their smallest, and approximately 1584(22) microm for L3 infective larvae. There was a great increase in length during stage 2 from approximately 322(27) to approximately 982(31) microm. Stage duration decreased with increasing temperature while growth rate increased, giving steeper growth curves. There was no effect of temperature on size, except for L3, which were shorter when mosquitoes were reared at higher temperature. It appears that larval growth is a continuous process from microfilariae to the young L3 stage, and continuously modifies the larval parasite aspect, even within each stage. Thus, information on larval shape may be used as an age indicator and in some cases, may give an estimation on time elapsed since infection of the vector. An important demographic parameter used in most mathematical models describing transmission of parasites by insect vectors is the length of the gonotrophic cycle of the vector, i.e. the time interval between two successive blood-meals. Usual methods for computing such a parameter are based on mark-recapture techniques. However, reliable estimates need substantial capture rates, which are not always possible. This paper presents another approach in which marked mosquitoes are those naturally infected by W. bancrofti. For one mosquito, the time since infection is simply the age of the developing larval parasite. Our method first expresses the age of larval parasite as a fraction of total development time (from microfilariae entering the vector to L3 larvae) using a regression model based on measurements of the parasite's length and width. This fraction of development is then converted to a chronological age since infection, using a back-calculation procedure involving ambient temperatures and growth rates of W. bancrofti larvae in the vector. The method is applied to wild caught Ae. polynesiensis in French Polynesia to compute the length of the gonotrophic cycle. This mosquito species comes to bite approximately 3, 6-7 and 9 days after a first infectious blood-meal. Then the length of the gonotrophic cycle may be of 3-4 days.</description><year>2002</year><authors>Lardeux, F., Cheffort, J.</authors><journal>International Journal for Parasitology</journal><volume-issue>32(6)</volume-issue><pages>705-716</pages><work_location>French Polynesia</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>French Polynesia/Lardeux and Cheffort 2002 Int J Parasitol 1-s2.0-S0020751901002909-main.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>