<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1460</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Books</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection; WHO Geneva</hardcopy_location><title>Monitoring and epidemiological assessment of the programme to eliminate lymphatic filariasis at implementation level</title><description>Overview: The Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis was launched in 2000 and since then has expanded its mass drug administration coverage with the recommended two-drug co-administration from 3 million people in 12 countries in 2000 to more than 70 million people in 36 countries in 2003. Throughout this period, the need for standardized guidelines on monitoring and epidemiological assessment of the Programme at implementation unit level has become increasingly evident because this is the level at which the core programmatic operations are conducted. These guidelines are based on current knowledge and understanding of the epidemiological aspects of the disease. However, in view of the rapid involvement of both scientific advances and experience in implementation of national elimination programmes, adaptation of the guidelines might be required to address particular circumstances. In light of the diverse responsibilities of the health personnel in charge of lymphatic filariasis elimination programmes, the authors have developed guidelines that are as concise as possible. Annexes have been included to provide the most relevant technical background information while avoiding too much detail in the body of the guidelines. Similar guidelines are planned to assist health personnel at the level of the implementation unit in other areas such as drug distribution, social mobilization and disability prevention and control.</description><year>2005</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>57</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Freely available from publisher website</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_1460.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>