<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1153</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Annual Reports</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis: Annual report on Lymphatic Filariasis 2002</title><description>Overview: This Annual Report highlights the progress made during 2002 in activities aimed at the worldwide elimination of lymphatic filariasis (LF) through the efforts of the Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis (GPELF). Lymphatic filariasis continues to be the major cause of disability in the world, and approximately 120 million people are infected. The disease is endemic in 80 countries and territories, 32 of which have implemented active elimination programmes – 10 more than in 2001. Nevertheless, the challenge remains considerable: although these 32 countries and territories represent almost 80% of the global at-risk population, they have covered only 5% of their own at-risk population with mass drug administration (MDA). Despite this, progress is encouraging since these countries reported a satisfactory drug coverage rate that established a promising foundation for future scaling-up of the elimination programmes.There is an urgent need to inject more energy into advocacy and fundraising: capacity building is a crucial component of the Global Programme and requires continuous enhancement. In addition, social and political support from the endemic countries is vital for the success of the Programme.</description><year>2002</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>118</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_2749.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>