<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>758</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection;JCU WHOCC; WHO DPS Fiji</hardcopy_location><title>Neglected tropical diseases of Oceania: review of their prevalence, distribution, and opportunities for control</title><description>Among Oceania's population of 35 million people, the greatest number living in poverty currently live in Papua New Guinea (PNG), Fiji, Vanuatu, and the Solomon Islands. These impoverished populations are at high risk for selected NTDs, including Necator americanus hookworm infection, strongyloidiasis, lymphatic filariasis (LF), balantidiasis, yaws, trachoma, leprosy, and scabies, in addition to outbreaks of dengue and other arboviral infections including Japanese encephalitis virus infection. PNG stands out for having the largest number of cases and highest prevalence for most of these NTDs. However, Australia's Aboriginal population also suffers from a range of significant NTDs. Through the Pacific Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis, enormous strides have been made in eliminating LF in Oceania through programs of mass drug administration (MDA), although LF remains widespread in PNG. There are opportunities to scale up MDA for PNG's major NTDs, which could be accomplished through an integrated package that combines albendazole, ivermectin, diethylcarbamazine, and azithromycin, in a program of national control. Australia's Aboriginal population may benefit from appropriately integrated MDA into primary health care systems. Several emerging viral NTDs remain important threats to the region.</description><year>2013</year><authors>Kline, K., McCarthy, J.S., Pearson, M., Loukas, A., Hotez, P.J.</authors><journal>PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases</journal><volume-issue>7(1)</volume-issue><pages>e1755</pages><work_location>Multicountry Pacific</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Multicountry Pacific/PacELF_758 Kline et al 2013 PLOS NTDs NTDs of Oceania review.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>