<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>970</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Transmission dynamics of lymphatic filariasis: density-dependence in the uptake of Wuchereria bancrofti microfilariae by vector mosquitoes</title><description>Gaining a better understanding of parasite infection dynamics in the vector mosquito (Diptera: Culicidae) population is central to improving knowledge regarding the transmission, persistence and hence control of lymphatic filariasis. Here, we use data on mosquito feeding experiments collated from the published literature to examine the available evidence regarding the functional form of the first component of this parasite-vector relationship for Wuchereria bancrofti (Filarioidea: Onchocercidae) causing Bancroftian filariasis, i.e. the rate of microfilariae (mf) uptake from the blood of infected humans by the feeding mosquito vector. Using a simple logarithmic regression model for describing the observed relationships between the mean numbers of mf ingested per mosquito and parasite load in humans in each study, and a linear mixed-effects meta-analytical framework for synthesizing the observed regressions across studies, we show here for the first time clear evidence for the existence of density-dependence in this process for all the three major filariasis transmitting mosquito vectors. An important finding of this study is that this regulation of mf uptake also varies significantly between the vector genera, being weakest in Culex, comparatively stronger in Aedes and most severe and occurring at significantly lower human mf loads in Anopheles mosquitoes. The analysis of the corresponding mf uptake prevalence data has further highlighted how density-dependence in mf uptake may influence the observed distributions of mf in vector populations. These results show that whereas strong regulation of mf uptake, especially when it leads to saturation in uptake at low human parasite intensities, can lead to static distributions of mf per mosquito with host parasite intensity, a weaker regulation of mf ingestion can give rise to changes in both mean mf loads and in the frequency distribution of parasites/mosquito with increasing human parasite intensity. These findings highlight the importance of considering local vector infection dynamics when attempting to predict the impacts of community-based filariasis control. They also emphasize the value of developing and applying robust meta-analytic methods for estimating functional relationships regarding parasitic infection from population ecological data.</description><year>2002</year><authors>Snow, L.C., Michael, E.</authors><journal>Medical and Veterinary Entomology</journal><volume-issue>16(4)</volume-issue><pages>409-423</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/Snow_et_al-2002-Medical_and_Veterinary_Entomology.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>