<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1152</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Annual Reports</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis: Annual report on lymphatic filariasis 2003</title><description>Overview: This Annual Report highlights the progress made during 2003 in activities aimed at the worldwide elimination of lymphatic filariasis (LF) through the efforts of the Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis (GPELF), which was launched in 1999. GPELF has expanded its mass drug administration (MDA) coverage with the recommended two-drug co-administration from a modest 3 million people in 12 countries in 2000 to more than 70 million in 36 countries during 2003. In addition, as part of an ongoing programme, India has covered an additional number of people with diethylcar-bamazine citrate (DEC) alone. In 2002, the population in the implementation units (IUs) covered exceeded the anticipated targets that were laid down in GPELF’s strategic plan developed in 1999. Encouraged by this rapid expansion, the partners of the Global Alliance to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis (GAELF) set the target for MDA coverage at 350 million people in 2005. Subsequently, a strategic plan for scaling up to achieve the target was developed in 2003 in consultation with partners, including the endemic countries. This strategic plan covering the period 2003–2005 was approved by TAG-LF. To ensure that this target is realistic, however, and to assess the resource requirements, each endemic country with an active programme was requested to provide a forecast of scaling up of MDA for the period 2004–2008. The forecast was to include funding requirements, with an indication of resources that would be provided by the ministry of health. Feedback has been received from the countries and is in the process of being analyzed. The results will be made available in due course.</description><year>2003</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>154</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_1152.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>