<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1215</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Guidelines and Instructional Materials</category><title>Lymphatic filariasis: A handbook of practical entomology = Filariose lympatique: entomologie practique</title><description>Overview: The Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis has scaled up its activities more rapidly than almost any other global public health programme. By the end of 2011, 53 of 73 endemic countries were implementing mass drug administration, and more than 3.9 billion treatments had been delivered to 952 million people. Challenges remain, however, in meeting the goal of eliminating the disease. Vector control is a possible complementary strategy in countries or areas (i) where mass drug administration has not started, such as those where loiasis is co-endemic; (ii) where the burden of lymphatic filariasis is heaviest and mass drug administration must be rapidly scaled up or (iii) where the expected impact of mass drug administration has not been achieved; and where local transmission has been interrupted to prevent recurrence. This document explains why vector control is important in national programmes and describes the preparation of a tailor-made control plan for national programmes. It outlines entomological procedures for regular and specific vector control and how data should be analysed for better overall understanding of filarial transmission and vectors. The document will also be useful for teaching personnel in lymphatic filariasis programmes about the use and value of entomological procedures in overall epidemiological appraisal in the context of elimination. Designed for national lymphatic elimination programme managers and for entomologists and parasitologists, this practical handbook will also be useful for programme staff working at regional and district levels, including those involved in vector control; development and technical agencies; nongovernmental organizations; and other organizations that support national programmes.</description><year>2013</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>107</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English; French</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Freely available from publisher website</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_1215.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>