<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>150</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Filariasis serosurvey, New Caledonia, South Pacific, 2013</title><description>BACKGROUND: Lymphatic filariasis (LF) is a major public health problem in the Pacific. As the global prevalence of infection was not known in New Caledonia (NC), a serosurvey study was conducted by determining the prevalence of circulating filarial antigens, as recommended by the World Health Organization. FINDINGS: A cross sectional study on a 2 degree stratified sample was carried out from June to November 2013. Inclusion criteria were: individuals aged 2 to 80 y/o, who had been hospitalized or sought medical care for a non-infectious cause and who had been living in NC for more than 6 months. LF antigenic detection was performed using the immunocromatographic BinaxNOW filariasis card test (ICT). Among the 1,035 individuals tested, 7 were antigenic. The overall LF antigenic prevalence was 0.62% (CI 95% [0.60-0.63]). All patients were unrelated to each other; none of them presented clinical symptoms of LF. Four of the 7 ICT positive patients reported having travelled to LF endemic areas, 2 patients had never traveled outside NC and the last one had only traveled in non-endemic areas. For the 7 ICT positive patients, the research of microfilariae in blood smears and filarial DNA by PCR was negative. CONCLUSION: The prevalence of filarial antigenemia in NC is less than 1%, the threshold that defines the filarial endemic areas for WHO. Nevertheless, as two patients who had never travelled outside NC and one who had only travelled to non-endemic areas were antigenic, we cannot conclude that NC is totally free of LF.</description><year>2015</year><authors>Daures, M., Champagnat, J., Pfannstiel, A., Ringuenoire, F., Grangeon, J.-P., Musso, D.</authors><journal>Parasites and Vectors</journal><volume-issue>8</volume-issue><pages>102</pages><work_location>New Caledonia</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>New Caledonia/PacELF_150 Daures et al 2015 Parasites and Vectors LF serosurvey New Caledonia s13071-015-0713-9.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>