<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>2176</PacELF_ID><type>Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Seasonal abundance, diel biting activity and parity of Aedes polynesiensis Marks and A. samoanus (Gruenberg) (Diptera: Culicidae) in Samoa</title><description>The seasonal abundance, biting cycle, age composition and survival of females of Aedes polynesiensis Marks and A. samoanus (Grünberg), the major vectors of subperiodic bancroftian filariasis, were studied in Samoa. A. polynesiensis density was low during the high rainfall months and increased immediately following them. A. samoanus density showed no clear relation to rainfall. A. polynesiensis was active throughout the day, with peaks indoors and out at 08.00–09.00 h and 16.00–18.00 h. The nulliparous and parous populations showed similar patterns of activity. The biting cycles of 2-parous and 3- plus 4-parous females were asymmetric with time. A. samoanus was active throughout the night, with highest activity at 23.00– 01.00 h. A minor peak at 19.00–20.00 h was more pronounced among older females than among younger ones. Night biting by A. polynesiensis and day biting by A. samoanus were rare. The parous proportion of A. polynesiensis ranged from 36·3 to 59·5% and the epidemiologically significant 3- plus 4-parous proportion ranged from 1·0 to 6·7%. The parous proportion of A. samoanus was 37·9–49·7% and the 3- plus 4-parous proportion 1·4–2·6%. The proportions found to be parous in both vectors were generally higher in the cool than the warm season, suggesting higher daily survival during that period.</description><year>1987</year><authors>Samarawickrema, W.A., Sone, F., Cummings, R.F.</authors><journal>Bulletin of Entomological Research</journal><volume-issue>77(2)</volume-issue><pages>191-200</pages><work_location>Samoa</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><decade>1980</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>