<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1687</PacELF_ID><type>Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>[Control of lymphatic filariasis infection and disease] = La lutte contre les filarioses lymphatiques</title><description>Recent advances in the diagnosis, treatment, and pathophysiology of lymphatic fllariasis have raised hopes for eradication. Development of an easy-touse, rapid-format diagnostic tool has facilitated precise location of infectious zones thus allowing quick intervention. Two new drugs, i.e., ivermectin and albendazole, have been shown to be highly effective in the management of microfilariasis due to Wuchereria bancrofti, Brugia malayi, and Brugia timori thus greatly expanding a therapeutic arsenal once limited to diethylcarbamazine. The current eradication strategy is designed to break the chain of transmission in populations exposed to the risk of infection by administering a single dose of two drugs yearly for five to six years. Combined treatment using albendazole plus ivermectin or albendazole plus diethylcarbamazine has resulted in near-zero microfilaremia levels for at least one year. Based on these new developments, the World Health Assembly adopted a resolution calling on member states to work for the elimination of lymphatic filariasis as a public health problem. Thanks to the donation of albendazole and ivermectin by SmithKline Beecham and Merck &amp; Co. respectively, the WHO has started a worldwide program and set up task force including a wide-range of actors in different fields for eradication of this disease affecting 120 million people.</description><year>2000</year><authors>Karam, M., Ottesen, E.</authors><journal>Medecine Tropicale</journal><volume-issue>60(3)</volume-issue><pages>291-296</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>French</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>