<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>694</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>The epidemiology and control of lymphatic filariasis on Lihir Island, New Ireland Province</title><description>Clinical, parasitological and entomological surveys performed in 9 villages on Lihir Island, Papua New Guinea, before mass treatment with diethylcarbamazine (DEC), showed that lymphatic filariasis, caused by nocturnally periodic Wuchereria bancrofti, was endemic in 8 of them. Blood samples from 593 people revealed an overall microfilarial carrier rate of 24%. Amongst endemic villages, microfilarial carrier rates ranged from 5% to 43% and there was no significant difference in parasite prevalence between males and females. Obstructive filarial disease, defined as lymphoedema of the limbs or hydrocele, was observed in only 2% of 262 males examined. None of the 265 females examined had clinical symptoms. Entomological surveys yielded a total of 4095 mosquitoes including 3,692 anophelines and 241 culicines but only Anopheles farauti was found to harbour infective larvae of W. bancrofti. Pretreatment infection and infective rates of An. farauti were 7% and 1% respectively and up to 12 infective larvae were found in a single specimen. The microfilarial carrier rate in a cohort of people who received two DEC treatments dropped from 59% to 32% but the difference was not statistically significant. However, density of microfilaraemia decreased significantly from 170 to 10 mf/ml. Biannual mass treatment with DEC significantly reduced vector infection rates and transmission intensity on Lihir.</description><year>2000</year><authors>Hii, J., Bockarie, M.J., Flew, S., Genton, B., Tali, A., Dagoro, H., Waulas, B., Samson, M., Alpers, M.P.</authors><journal>Papua and New Guinea Medical Journal</journal><volume-issue>43(3-4)</volume-issue><pages>188-195</pages><work_location>Papua New Guinea</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Papua New Guinea/Hii et al 2000 PNG Med J Lihir LF The epidemiology - Sep_Dec 2000.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>