<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1060</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Exploratory study investigating factors influencing mass drug administration (MDA) compliance for lymphatic filariasis in Samoa</title><description>Successful elimination of lymphatic filariasis (LF) requires a multi-faceted approach. In Samoa, persistent transmission in residual areas, despite many years of mass drug administrations (MDAs), may be in part due to systematic MDA non-compliance of infected individuals. These individuals could potentially remain as reservoirs of infection, thus impeding successful elimination of LF in Samoa. Data were available for five villages where epidemiological prevalence studies are currently being conducted. Individuals testing positive for LF and children aged 7 to 10 years were asked to participate in a small questionnaire de-signed to ascertain: 1) level of knowledge of LF, (2) compliance, and, (3) a small number of select risk factors. For the dataset from infected per-sons, there was a significant association between MDA compliance and knowledge of LF and, for the children, this association also extended to use of mosquito protection. Of those infected, 33% admitted to being systematically non-compliant. This exploratory study highlights the need for re-structuring current educational campaigns and their deliverance to appropriately target children and the systematically non-compliant infected individuals. In order to improve compliance, focus needs to be on motivation by informing the individuals of the benefits of MDA compliance versus the dire effects of disease. These findings are critical for the Samoan LF program and should help initiate updating current educational material to improve compliance. Without securing higher rates of compliance amongst those infected, successful elimination of LF in Samoa will be challenging.</description><year>2010</year><authors>Joseph, H., Clough, A., Peteru, A., Crawley, S., Pulu, T., Maiava, F., Melrose, W.</authors><journal>Samoa Medical Journal</journal><volume-issue>2(3)</volume-issue><pages>12-25</pages><work_location>Samoa</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Samoa/Joseph et al 2010 SAMOA MED J Compliance data Samoa.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>