<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>504</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Productivity of natural and artificial containers for Aedes polynesiensis and Aedes aegypti in four American Samoan villages</title><description>Six mosquito species were identified in a survey of containers associated with 347 households in four villages in American Samoa. Aedes polynesiensis Marks (Diptera: Culicidae) and Aedes aegypti (L) were the most abundant species, representing 57% and 29% of the mosquitoes identified. Culex quinquefasciatus (Say), Culex annulirostris (Skuse), Aedes oceanicus (Belkin) and Toxorhynchites amboinensis (Doleschall) were also found. Aedes aegypti and Ae. polynesiensis showed distinct differences in their use of containers, preferring large and small containers, respectively. By contrast with previous studies, Ae. polynesiensis utilized domestic and natural containers with equal frequency, whereas Ae. aegypti continued to be found predominantly in domestic containers. Only 15% of containers holding immature mosquitoes included pupae and fewer than 10 Aedes spp. pupae were found in most containers with pupae. An estimated 2289 Ae. polynesiensis and 1640 Ae. aegypti pupae were found in 2258 containers. The presence of both species in the same container did not affect the mean density of either species for larvae or pupae. Glass jars, leaf axils, tree holes and seashells produced few Aedes spp. pupae in any of the study villages. Overall, 75% of Ae. polynesiensis pupae were found in buckets, ice-cream containers and tyres, with &lt;7% being produced in natural containers, whereas 82% of Ae. aegypti pupae were found in 44-gallon (US) drums ( approximately 166L), buckets and tyres. Source reduction efforts targeting these container types may yield significant reductions in both Ae. polynesiensis and Ae. aegypti populations in American Samoa.</description><year>2007</year><authors>Burkot, T.R., Handzel, T., Schmaedick, M.A., Tufa, J., Roberts, J.M., Graves, P.M.</authors><journal>Medical and Veterinary Entomology</journal><volume-issue>21(1)</volume-issue><pages>22-29</pages><work_location>American Samoa</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>American Samoa/PacELF_504 Burkot et al 2007 MED VET ENT .pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>