<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>891</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Detection and characterization of Wolbachia infections in Wuchereria bancrofti (Spirurida: Onchocercidae) var. pacifica and Aedes (Stegomyia) polynesiensis (Diptera: Culicidae)</title><description>Despite control programs based on mass drug administration (MDA) of microfilaricidal compounds, Bancroftian lymphatic filariasis remains a problem in French Polynesia. For an alternative strategy to MDA, we investigated the potential role of Wolbachia to control filarial transmission. Wolbachia are intracellular alpha-proteobacteria endosymbionts that infect a broad range of insects and nematodes. These bacteria have a suspected role in the pathogenesis of filariasis. They also may be useful in mosquito control through cytoplasmic incompatibility. To detect and characterize these bacteria in the filarial and mosquito-vectors in French Polynesia, a survey was conducted on field-collected mosquitoes and microfilariae from infected people. Samples were analyzed by a polymerase chain reaction and gene sequencing. The results indicate that these bacteria are widespread. Sequence analysis of the wsp and ftsZ genes positioned the Aedes polynesiensis Wolbachia in cluster A and Wuchereria bancrofti var. pacifica Wolbachia in cluster D. The implications for possible improved treatment and vector control are discussed.</description><year>2005</year><authors>Plichart, C., Legrand, A.-M.</authors><journal>American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene</journal><volume-issue>73(2)</volume-issue><pages>354-358</pages><work_location>French Polynesia</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>French Polynesia/Plichart and LeGrand 2005 ASTMH Detection of Wolbachia in W bancrofti and Ae poly.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>