<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>642</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Circulating fibrosis markers, eosinophil cationic protein and eosinophil protein X in patients with Wuchereria bancrofti infection: association with clinical status</title><description>We measured the concentrations of several circulating fibrosis markers (type I collagen I, type III procollagen, hyaluronan) and eosinophil granule proteins (ECP and EPX) in lymphatic filariasis patients to investigate their relationship with clinical, parasitological and immunological data. This study was conducted in Polynesian patients with various stages of the disease (acute lymphangitis, chyluria, hydrocoele, elephantiasis), a closely related microbial lymphangitis and endemic controls. We observed modifications of the different markers in this pathology. Serum type I collagen and PIIINP were decreased. Serum hyaluronan, linked to perilymphatic granulomatous inflammation, was significantly increased in acute lymphangitis and elephantiasis patients. Serum ECP was also increased, at the limit of significance in our sample, in elephantiasis patients. These two last markers, already validated in another helminth disease, schistosomiasis, have potential interest in terms of follow-up of morbidity in these parasitic diseases.</description><year>2006</year><authors>Esterre, P., Plichart, C., Huin-Blondey, M.O., Nguyen, L.N., Hartmann, D., Guerret, S., Reimert, C.M., Ricard-Blum, S.</authors><journal>Parasite</journal><volume-issue>13(2)</volume-issue><pages>165-170</pages><work_location>French Polynesia</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>French Polynesia/Esterre et al 2006 PARASITE Circulating fibrosis markers, eosinophil cationic protein.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>