<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>877</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>WHO Geneva; JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection; JCU WHOCC</hardcopy_location><title>Towards a strategic plan for research to support the Global Program to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis: summary of immediate needs and opportunities for research on lymphatic filariasis identified by the filariasis community of scientists in association with an "LF Research Forum", convened in Philadelphia, December 9-10, 2003.</title><description>[Extract from Executive Summary] The Global Program to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis (GPELF), now four years old and clearly providing enormous health benefits from its broad deworming effects in the poorest sectors of the developing world, represents a societal investment already measured in the tens of millions of dollars. Despite rapid progress in scaling up the program to more than 38 endemic countries (or perhaps even because of this rapid progress), there is one element essential for ultimate program success that is now being severely neglected-research, both operational and basic (upstream) ... It was toward this end that efforts were made during 2003−2004 to gather diverse and valued input from a very broad representation of the filariasis community, both program and research oriented. More than 90 research, clinical, and public health experts in LF came together in meetings (Annexes 1−3) and deliberations for the purpose of creating a comprehensive, collective assessment of today’s LF research horizon and research needs. While there was broad agreement that the GPELF remains very much on target, in-depth assessments were made of ways to improve program support or increase understanding for each of the most important issues related to operational and basic, upstream research. For each of these domains, needs and opportunities were first defined and then prioritized.</description><year>2004</year><authors>Various</authors><journal>The American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene</journal><volume-issue>71(5)</volume-issue><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/ASTMH 2004 strategy for research on LF.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>