<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>2767</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Reports and Results</category><title>Provisional strategy for interrupting lymphatic filariasis transmission in loiasis-endemic countries</title><description>Overview: The Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis targets the global elimination of lymphatic filariasis as a public-health problem by 2020. The main strategy is to interrupt transmission through integrated preventive chemotherapy, using mass drug administration to treat entire populations at risk of the disease, with a combination of albendazole plus ivermectin or albendazole plus diethylcarbamazine administered as a single dose once a year for at least 5 years. Because ivermectin or diethylcarbamazine can cause serious adverse effects in people infected with Loa loa causing loiasis (African eye worm), an endemic disease in a large part of central Africa, the current guidelines for preventive chemotherapy contain no recommendation for areas where lymphatic filariasis and loiasis are co-endemic but where onchocerciasis is hypo-endemic or non-endemic. Consequently, mass drug administration to eliminate lymphatic filariasis using the combination of medicines recommended by the World Health Organization could thus far not be implemented in these communities. In order to meet the 2020 goal, it has become urgent to develop an alternative strategy for interrupting transmission of lymphatic filariasis adapted to the specific situation of co-endemicity with Loa loa. This strategy could potentially include both medication and vector control. The milestones for the Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis 2010–2020 stipulate that by 2012, a provisional strategy for interrupting lymphatic filariasis transmission in loiasis-endemic countries should have been developed; and that by 2013, a revised strategy for interrupting lymphatic filariasis transmission should have been implemented in all loiasis-endemic countries. In June 2011, a preliminary meeting on Loa loa in Lusaka, Zambia, proposed the following provisional strategies for eliminating lymphatic filariasis in areas where Loa loa is co-endemic: integrated vector management as the main strategy, and mapping of lymphatic filariasis and Loa loa at the lowest possible administrative level to potentially identify small areas that can be treated for lymphatic filariasis.</description><year>2012</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>25</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Freely available from publisher website</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_2767.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>