<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>2741</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Action/Strategic Plans</category><title>Building partnerships for lymphatic filariasis: strategic plan (working version: September 1999)</title><description>Overview: Lymphatic filariasis (LF) commonly known as elephantiasis, is a painful and profoundly disfiguring disease that has a major social and economic impact in Asia, Africa, the Western Pacific and parts of the Americas. Until recently, little could be done to relieve the suffering and disability caused by this disease. Today, however, significant advances have been made in understanding both the disease and its control. A global coalition has been forged among many organizations, each with a different mandate but all having a common goal: to tackle the wide-ranging and complex process of science and practice that will result in the elimination of LF as a public health problem1 from the world. A strong start was made in 1997 when the World Health Assembly passed a resolution calling for ' ... the elimination of lymphatic filariasis as a public health problem ... '. Following this, WHO, with support from organizations including donor countries, the World Bank, the Arab Fund for Economic and Social Development, and the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention began developing a coalition to eliminate the disease. The following year the coalition was given a powerful boost when SmithKiine Beech am announced its commitment to form a unique private-sector/public-sector collaboration with WHO to support the global programme to eliminate lymphatic filariasis. The two organizations pledged to work together closely to undertake this massive international public health effort. Subsequently, Merck &amp; Co., Inc. pledged to expand its ongoing Mectizan® Donation Program for onchocerciasis to cover treatment of lymphatic filariasis in all African countries where the two diseases occur together. Individually, none of these organizations can eliminate LF; but by working together, and working through the Ministries of Health in the endemic countries, we believe that it can be done. Not all partners will work in each country, but, together, we hope to develop partnerships that will cover all of the affected countries and ensure an extraordinarily positive impact on many millions of lives.</description><year>1999</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>50</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_2741.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>1990</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>