<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1207</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Guidelines and Instructional Materials</category><title>Lymphoedema staff manual: treatment and prevention of problems associated with lymphatic filariasis. Part 1. Learner's guide</title><description>Overview: This training module on the treatment and prevention of lymphoedema due to lymphatic filariasis (LF) consists of two separate parts: Part 1 (this part), the Learner’s Guide, contains all the technical information needed by health workers involved in disability alleviation and prevention. Part 2, the Tutor’s Guide, outlines the main learning points and provides guidance on the learning process for those responsible for conducting training programmes. This document is part of a series on several topics related to lymphatic filariasis that will be produced by the World Health Organization to assist national elimination programmes on the different aspects of the disease. Addressing the social hardships and alleviating of the physical suffering of individuals affected by the chronic manifestations of lymphatic filariasis (lymphoedema, hydrocoele, elephantiasis of the limbs or genitals, and the secondary infections associated with damaged lymphatics) are vital elements of the strategy to eliminate lymphatic filariasis. This training module is the first attempt to address the needs of patients affected by lymphoedema and is based on experience from small-scale interventions in limited areas in Brazil and Haiti. Lessons learned from the scaling-up of these interventions in other countries will provide the critical information required to define an effective, affordable and simple approach to the management of lymphoedema at community level. This information will ensure a solid basis for the production of new training materials for health personnel and different levels of the health system in order to scale-up the public health interventions of this essential component of LF elimination in national programmes. Contributions from all concerned health professionals, particularly from the fields will be essential to succeed in this challenge.</description><year>2001</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>87</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_1207.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>