<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>737</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Lymphatic filariasis and onchocerciasis prevention, treatment, and control costs across diverse settings: a systematic review</title><description>The control and eventual elimination of neglected tropical disease (NTD) requires the expansion of interventions such as mass drug administration (MDA), vector control, diagnostic testing, and effective treatment. The purpose of this paper is to present the evidence base for decision-makers on the cost and cost-effectiveness of lymphatic filariasis (LF) and onchocerciasis prevention, treatment, and control. A systematic review of the published literature was conducted. All studies that contained primary or secondary data on costs or cost-effectiveness of prevention and control were considered. A total of 52 papers were included for LF and 24 papers were included for onchocerciasis. Large research gaps exist on the synergies and cost of integrating NTD prevention and control programs, as well as research on the role of health information systems, human resource systems, service delivery, and essential medicines and technology for elimination. The literature available on costs and cost-effectiveness of interventions is also generally older, extremely focal geographically and of limited usefulness for developing estimates of the global economic burden of these diseases and prioritizing among various intervention options. Up to date information on the costs and cost-effectiveness of interventions for LF and onchocerciasis prevention are needed given the vastly expanded funding base for the control and elimination of these diseases. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><year>2014</year><authors>Keating, J., Yukich, J.O., Mollenkopf, S., Tediosi, F.</authors><journal>Acta Tropica</journal><volume-issue>135</volume-issue><pages>86-95</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/Keating et al 2014 Acta Tropica LF and Oncho cost eff systematic review 1-s2.0-S0001706X14001004-main.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>