<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>911</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><title>Toward the elimination of lymphatic filariasis by 2020: treatment update and impact assessment for the endgame</title><description>Lymphatic filariasis (LF) is an important public health problem endemic in 73countries, where it is a major cause of acute and chronic morbidity and a significant impediment to socioeconomic development. It is targeted for elimination by 2020, through preventive chemotherapy using albendazole in combination with either ivermectin or diethylcarbamazine citrate. Preventive chemotherapy enables the regular and coordinated administration of safe, single-dose medications delivered through mass drug administration (MDA). Many countries are now scaling down MDA activities after achieving 100% geographic coverage and instituting monitoring and evaluation procedures to establish the impact of several consecutive rounds of MDA and determine if transmission has been interrupted. At the same time, countries yet to initiate MDA for elimination of LF will adopt improved mapping and coverage assessment protocols to accelerate the efforts for achieving global elimination by 2020. This review provides an update on treatment for LF and describes the current global status of the elimination efforts, transmission control processes and strategies for measuring impact and continuing surveillance after MDA has ceased.</description><year>2013</year><authors>Rebollo, M.P., Bockarie, M.J.</authors><journal>Expert Review of Anti-Infective Therapy</journal><volume-issue>11(7)</volume-issue><pages>723-731</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/Rebollo &amp; Bockarie 2013 EXP REV ANTI INF THER Towards the elimination of LF by 2020 out.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2010</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>