<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>1154</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Annual Reports</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Global Programme to Eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis: Annual report on lymphatic filariasis 2001</title><description>Overview: This report highlights the progress made during the year 2001 in activities aimed at the elimination of lymphatic filariasis (LF) worldwide. There are more than a billion people who are at risk of lymphatic filariasis, which is not a killer disease. The infection is caused by thread- like worms (filariae) which lodge in the lymphatic system, producing millions of minute larvae (microfilariae) that circulate in the blood. Although infection often occurs in childhood, the symptoms are commonly delayed until adulthood. Over 120 million people are currently living with the disease, including about 40 million who are incapacitated and disfigured by it. Of all diseases, lymphatic filariasis is the second leading cause of permanent and long-term disability. Until recently, the diagnosis of lymphatic filariasis depended on night blood examinations to detect microfilariae. Now, there is an antigen-detection test that can be taken at any time of the day, making it feasible to map the disease geographically. Drugs, which are available free or at low cost, kill the microfilariae in the blood. Simple methods of hygiene and self-care can reduce the effects of the disease. With such effective tools to hand, the Fiftieth World Health Assembly, in 1997, resolved to eliminate lymphatic filariasis as a public health problem. This report discusses the progress so far.</description><year>2001</year><authors>World Health Organization</authors><pages>81</pages><work_location>Multicountry Global</work_location><language>English</language><publisher>World Health Organization</publisher><access_rights>Open</access_rights><pdf_file_name>MULTICOUNTRY Global/PacELF_2771.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>2000</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>