<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>849</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection;JCU WHOCC</hardcopy_location><title>Enquete sur la filariose lymphatique dans l'Ile d'Ouvéa en Nouvelle-Caledonie [Study of Bancroftian filariasis on Ouvea Island in New Caledonia]</title><description>Several cases of Bancroftian filariasis were recently reported on Ouvea Island which is part of the archipelago of New Caledonia located in the south Pacific Ocean. Following these reports systematic screening was carried out in a group of 382 adult consultees at two medical dispensaries. Tests to detect microfilariae in the blood and antibodies in serum were performed at the Pasteur Institute in New Caledonia and the Malarde Institute in Papeete, French Polynesia, respectively. Of the two subjects with manifestations consistent with filariasis, one was seropositive but neither presented microfilariae. Overall 14 subjects (3.7 p. 100) presented microfilariae and 124 were seropositive (33.5 p. 100). The serologic index was significantly higher in men than in women (6.1 p. 100 vs 2.1 p. 100). Parasitic and serologic indexes were significantly higher (p &lt; 0.001) in subjects living in the northern than southern part of the island. As in previous studies in New Caledonia, present data showed that Bancrofitian filariasis is asymptomatic on Ouvea Island. This finding contrasts with the symptomatic forms described on other islands in the south Pacific.</description><year>1999</year><authors>Monchy, D., Barny, S., Rougier, Y., Baudet, J.M., Gentile, B.</authors><journal>Medecine Tropicale</journal><volume-issue>59(2)</volume-issue><pages>146-150</pages><work_location>New Caledonia</work_location><language>French</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>New Caledonia/Monchy et al 1999 MED TROP LF Ouvea New Caledonia (French).pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>1990</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>