<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document xmlns:rdsi.pacelf.phase3='http://www.example.com' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' ><PacELF_ID>746</PacELF_ID><type>Electronic/Hardcopy</type><category>Scientific Papers</category><hardcopy_location>JCU WHOCC; JCU WHOCC Ichimori collection</hardcopy_location><title>Low-density microfilaraemia in subperiodic bancroftian filariasis in Samoa</title><description>Among microfilaria (mf) carriers of subperiodic bancroftian filariasis in Samoa, the low-density level of microfilaraemia was defined as 1-20 mf/ml, and the occurrence of low-density carriers (90 in the present study) was analysed by age, sex, and village in relation to the microfilarial prevalence rate. The low-density carriers were more numerous among those under 20 years and over 60 years old than in other age groups. The ratio of low-density carriers to the total of mf-positive subjects in a village decreased as the prevalence rate of Wuchereria bancrofti in the village increased.The epidemiological significance of low-density carriers was assessed in connection with the infectivity of vector mosquitos (Aedes polynesiensis) produced by them, the possible change of these carriers to carriers of a higher density, and the production of new low-density carriers by diethylcarbamazine citrate (DEC-C) treatment. The mosquito infectivity produced by the low-density carriers accounted for only 2.16% of the total infectivity produced by all the carriers, suggesting that these carriers are of minor importance in the transmission of filariasis. The change of microfilarial count over time among untreated mf-positive subjects was not remarkable during a 60-252-day observation period. However, the low-density carrier group showed a mean increase of 36%, the younger such carriers (under 30 years old) showing a 132% increase. The production of low-density carriers by DEC-C single-dose treatment (6 mg/kg body weight) was not as great as expected.</description><year>1985</year><authors>Kimura, E., Penaia, L., Samarawickrema, W.A., Spears, G.F.S.</authors><journal>Bulletin of the World Health Organization</journal><volume-issue>63(6)</volume-issue><pages>1089-1096</pages><work_location>Samoa</work_location><language>English</language><access_rights>Restricted</access_rights><pdf_file_name>Samoa/PacELF_746 Kimura et al 1985 BULL WHO MF in Samoa bullwho00089-0118.pdf</pdf_file_name><decade>1980</decade></rdsi.pacelf.phase3:document>